FRANZ CHEN

८ (+1) 647 667 7298 - **☑** franzjchen@gmail.com - **۞** Dendrimer

SUMMARY

Experienced in developing scalable web services and APIs on cloud infrastructure

LANGUAGES, FRAMEWORKS AND TOOLS

Languages Go, Python, Java, C, Rust, C++, Javascript, Scala, PHP

Tools Docker, Kubernetes, Apache Spark, Redis, AWS, MySQL, Git, Linux, Bash

EXPERIENCE

Wattpad

May 2016 - August 2016

Associate Engineer - Platform

- · Developed a subscription data storage microservice in Go, designed caching strategies to optimize its throughput, and deployed it on AWS with Docker and Kubernetes
- · Overhauled a client event data parsing pipeline written in Scala with Apache Spark which ingested hundreds of GBs of data per day, increasing its speed, resource efficiency, and ease of use
- · Maintained a legacy PHP backend monolith by refactoring code for clarity and ease of maintenance

PayTM Labs

September 2016 - December 2016

Data Engineer

- · Created an internal web tool for employee onboarding with Django and MySQL and deployed it on AWS with Docker
- · Wrote a service in Python to collect and analyze performance metrics from AWS and bare metal servers

Acquia

January 2016 - April 2016

Java Developer

- · Developed web applications with MVP architecture using Java EE and GWT
- · Implemented client state logic using Java, JDBC, MySQL, Hibernate and Liquibase

PROJECTS

One Press - 2nd Place at UofT Hacks 2016

github.com/Dendrimer/Onepressman

- · This project was an Android and Pebble application for easing emergency communication by allowing users to text 911 and other contacts preconfigured messages with the push of a button on their Pebble
- · Wrote the components for communication between the Android and Pebble apps, as well as the components for texting other mobile phones

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo

June 2019 (expected)

Bachelors of Applied Science in Computer Engineering

- · Courses: Operating Systems, Compilers, Data Structures and Algorithms
- · Member of the Water Boys, University of Waterloo's internationally competitive A Capella group